Lilya SUCHKOVA

+7-(916)-000-90-76 ◆ ssaaakova@icloud.com Moscow ◆ Russia

https://www.linkedin.com/in/lil-suchkova/

Data Scientist and Analyst with solid academic background, 6 years of experience in e-commerce and banking. I perform analytics, build and utilize machine learning models for banks' campaigning in order to understand consumer behavior and their preferences, which helps to increase company's profit and customer satisfaction.

I am looking for a Data Scientist / Machine Learning Engineer position in the Nordic countries.

EXPERIENCE

Rosbank, Soci'et'e G'en'erale Group

Jan 2021 - present

Data Scientist – Retail Business, Customer Experience Modeling

Moscow

- Developed model for private loans demand elasticity prediction and conducted A/B test on its effect
- Currently developing models for private loans response rate and refinance take rate predictions
 Tools: Python (numpy, pandas, sklearn, lightGBM), SAS

SberBank Sep 2019 - Jan 2021

Data Scientist - Retail Business, Mass Personalization

Moscow

- Developed and maintained machine learning models to predict response on investment and savings products: deposits, broker accounts and other:
 - My new metal accounts response prediction model increased uplift 3.5x times and generated additional NPV of 2.6 mln USD per Q2 2020
 - Developed model for predicting financial literacy level for the project that won Best Social Project award at Retail Finance Awards 2020
- · Completed ad-hoc analysis on clients' savings behavior and helped to design A/B tests for campaign efficiency evaluation

Tools: Python (numpy, pandas, sklearn, lightGBM), SQL (Teradata), SAS

SberBank Nov 2015 - Sep 2019

Financial Data Analyst – Treasury, Funds Transfer Pricing

Moscow

- Developed and maintained model for basis risk premium evaluation for internal funding of long-term projects with floating loan rates to mitigate interest rate risk
- Developed custom-made methods for measuring rationality of exercising embedded options for retail deposits (withdrawal and top-up)
- Completed regular and ad-hoc analytic reports on interest rates, balance sheet structure and dynamics, prepared documents for Rates Committee and Assets-Liabilities Management Committee

Tools: MS Excel (+VBA), SQL (MS SQL Server, Teradata), R, Python

Lamoda Jun 2015 - Oct 2015

Data Analyst – Business Development & Customer Insights

Moscow

- · Developed from scratch a report on regional sales and customer preferences' difference
- Prepared ad-hoc analytics on customer behavior: prepayment systems comparison, orders cancellation measurement
- · Maintained regular reports on customer feedback

Tools: MS Excel, SQL (Oracle), Hive

EDUCATION

Higher School of Economics, Moscow

M.Sc. in Data Science & Financial Technologies

Jul 2019

GPA: 4.5/5.0

Relevant courses: Machine Learning, NLP, Deep Learning, Big Data, Stochastic Processes & Time Series

M.Sc. in Financial Economics

Jun 2015

GPA: 4.8/5.0, cum laude

Relevant courses: Econometrics, Financial Markets & Instruments, Game Theory

B.Sc. Applied Mathematics & Computer Science

Jun 2013

GPA: 4.85/5.0, cum laude

Relevant courses: Optimization, Game Theory & Social Choice, Probability Theory & Statistics, Databases,

Programming (C++, C#, MATLAB)

SKILLS

Programming Python (numpy, pandas, matplotlib, sklearn, lightGBM, XGBoost)

Databases MS SQL Server, Teradata

Models logistic regression, decision trees, gradient boosting, clustering, t-SNE

Other data visualization, statistics, A/B testing

Tools SAS, git, bash, VS Code, Jupyter Notebook, Google Colab

Languages English (fluent), Russian (native)

OTHER CERTIFICATIONS

Introduction to PySpark, DataCamp

Introduction to Data Engineering, DataCamp

Machine Learning PRO Accelerator, SkillFactory

Data Visualization with Python by IBM, Coursera

Machine Learning with TensorFlow on GCP (2/5 courses) by Google, Coursera

Sep 2020